<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: bitcoin | What she said]]></title>
  <link href="http://weilu.github.io/blog/categories/bitcoin/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://weilu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-11T14:21:40+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://weilu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Wei Lu]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[luwei.here@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perks of Being an HD Wallet]]></title>
    <link href="http://weilu.github.io/blog/2014/07/11/perks-of-being-an-hd-wallet/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-11T08:27:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://weilu.github.io/blog/2014/07/11/perks-of-being-an-hd-wallet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The technical crowd in Bitcoin land has been excited about hierarchical deterministic(HD) wallet since the day it came out. But what benefits exactly does it bring to regular end users?</p>

<p>tl;dr much more simplified backup + better privacy</p>

<p>To understand why that is the case, we need to start with how non-HD wallet works.</p>

<h2>The non-HD way</h2>

<p>The primary job of a wallet is to manage your keys. To spend any funds, the wallet needs to find private keys(s) that correspond to the spendable funds. To receive any funds, the wallet needs to tell you what is the address that corresponds to a private key that it's aware of. Previously, we've already established that <a href="/blog/2014/06/08/bitcoin-address-reuse/">it is bad to use a single address for all your transactions</a>. But why do wallets still do it? A single address is the default setting for most wallets because it has its perks. For wallets, from a technical point of view, a single address is easy to manage. A user backs up his/her one and only private key and be done with it for good. For users new to Bitcoin, the bank account analogy stands, so less confusion for users. Privacy seems like a reasonable price to pay.</p>

<p>Some wallets allow users to create more addresses. I guess the rationale is that those who care to create more addresses are power users who more or less know some inner workings of Bitcoin. So they shall be given the freedom to manage their own addresses/keys. But here's the catch, in case you don't already know, every time you create a new address, you need to back up your wallet. Why? The point of a backup is to save another copy of all your private keys that correspond to addresses that you have unspent funds or can potentially receive funds at in the future. So in case that you lose the device that has your wallet which holds all the private keys, you can still access your funds on another device by importing the backup keys. In case one forgets to carry out a backup in time, he/she risks losing funds that are sent to the addresses whose corresponding private keys are not among the backed up keys.</p>

<p>In short, in the non-HD land, as a user, if you want to avoid address reuse and ensure the safety of your funds at the same time, you'd have to go through the inconvenience of carrying out backups whenever you creates a new address. Is there a way we can avoid this privacy/fund security/convenience trade-off? And even better, can we have wallets abstract away the key/address management from users altogether?</p>

<h2>HD wallets come to the rescue</h2>

<p>The technical specs of hierachical deterministic wallets are defined by <a href="https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0032.mediawiki">BIP32</a>. The gist of BIP32 is that it defines how a tree of private keys can be derived from a single master key in a deterministic manner. "Hierarchical" refers to the tree-like structure. "Deterministic" means that so long as one follows the specs, a given master key is guaranteed to always produces the exact same tree regardless of how many times one carries out the derivation. HD wallets have many potential applications. Here, I'm only going to focus on how it solves the above-mentioned problems with the non-HD wallets.</p>

<p><img src="/images/post/2014-07-11-tree.png" title="Not only is that terrible in general, but you just KNOW Billy's going to open the root present first, and then everyone will have to wait while the heap is rebuilt." alt="xkcd tree" /></p>

<p>^^ A tree-like structure</p>

<p>With BIP32, the line between the user responsibilities and wallet responsibilities is clear -- user keeps the master key safe; and it's the only backup he/she will ever need. While the wallet generates keys in the tree when necessary, for example, whenever an address is used for receiving funds, the wallet generates the next address in line to be used for the next transaction. The user always gives out the current address wallet displays for optimal privacy, while the wallet needs to watch all the addresses it has ever generated for the purpose of receiving funds. In case a user loses his/her device that has the wallet, they can enter their master key in an HD wallet on another device. The wallet goes ahead and derive the tree of private keys, scans each key for funds. And there we go, a wallet recovered.</p>

<p>Enough said, embrace HD wallet, for simpler backup and better privacy :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitcoin Address Reuse]]></title>
    <link href="http://weilu.github.io/blog/2014/06/08/bitcoin-address-reuse/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-08T14:28:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://weilu.github.io/blog/2014/06/08/bitcoin-address-reuse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When one is first introduced to Bitcoin, a bank account number is often used as an analogy for a Bitcoin address. Then you hear that it is bad to use the same Bitcoin address for all your transactions. I was asked by three different people something along the lines of</p>

<blockquote><p>If I give the same bank account number to different people who want to pay me, why do I need to give out different Bitcoin addresses to different people?</p></blockquote>

<p>The short answer is: Address reuse is bad for privacy and potentially security under certain circumstances.</p>

<h2>Privacy</h2>

<p><strong>Scenario:</strong> My salary is paid in Bitcoin (reality). I use a single Bitcoin address for everything (fictional). You and I are friends (fictional, obviously).</p>

<p><strong>The story:</strong> Say we have a good time hanging out in a bar. Your significant other calls -- it's time to head home. I cover the bill because you don't have any cash. Later you want to pay me back. I give you my one and only Bitcoin address to receive payment. You send some coins to it. You want to check if the transaction is confirmed. You look it up on blockchain.info. While you are at it, you click on the address, noticing that every month on the first day I receive the same amount of bitcoins. And the amount isn't trivial. Bam! It doesn't take a genius to deduce that it's my salary.</p>

<p><strong>Explanation:</strong> It comes down to the fact that all Bitcoin transactions are public. Given an address, anyone can look up transactions ever sent to and from this address. This is where the bank account number analogy breaks down, because the transaction history of a bank account is private by default.</p>

<p>By giving out a fresh address every time, the payer isn't able to learn about your past transaction history by looking up the address he/she has in hand.</p>

<h2>Security</h2>

<p><strong>Scenario:</strong> Your operation system has a weakass <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random_number_generation">random number generator</a> (fictional-ish, at some point <a href="https://bitcoin.org/en/alert/2013-08-11-android">it was true for Android</a>). You use a single Bitcoin address for everything (fictional, I hope).</p>

<p><img src="/images/post/2014-06-08-random.png" title="RFC 1149.5 specifies 4 as the standard IEEE-vetted random number." alt="xkcd random number" /></p>

<p>^^ Your random number generator</p>

<p><strong>The story:</strong> Because of your weakass random number generator, your two transactions dated four days apart are signed with the same "random" number. Bam! Some smartpants figures out your private key by staring at your two transactions for long enough. You lost all your bitcoins.</p>

<p><strong>Explanation:</strong> Every time you send some coins, a transaction is created and signed with your private key that corresponds to your Bitcoin address. A random number generator is involved to add some randomness to your signature because that makes it secure <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elliptic_Curve_DSA#Signature_generation_algorithm">according to mathematics</a>. By having a single Bitcoin address, all transactions you ever make are signed with the same private key. More than one transaction made with the same key + same "random" number in signature = vulnerability.</p>

<p>By using different addresses as the source of funds for every transaction, you avoid signing more than one transaction with the same private key. So even with a bad random number generator, the vulnerability described above no longer applies.</p>

<p>There you have it, why reusing Bitcoin addresses is bad. Until next time,</p>

<blockquote><p>Vires in Numeris</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
